<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Projects</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 19:31:28 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learn Html</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 19:31:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/html/</guid>
      <description>Embark on Your Web Journey: Learning Basic HTML The Language of the Web HTML serves as the backbone of every webpage you encounter on the internet. It&amp;rsquo;s the language that structures the content you see and interact with daily. At its core, HTML is remarkably intuitive, employing tags to define different elements within a webpage. These tags act as building blocks, shaping the layout, content, and functionality of websites.
Empowering Creativity and Innovation One of the most compelling aspects of HTML is its versatility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a CoilGun (Guass Rifle)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/coilgun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 19:31:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/coilgun/</guid>
      <description>Intoroduction A Gauss rifle, also known as a coil gun, is a fascinating electromagnetic device that accelerates ferromagnetic projectiles using high-voltage coils. This article delves into the intricacies of multistage coilguns, exploring the necessary components, principles, and applications of this technology.
Multistage Coilgun A multistage coilgun is a sophisticated electromagnetic launcher comprised of multiple coil stages arranged along a barrel. Each stage contributes to the acceleration of the projectile, resulting in significant velocity gains over the length of the barrel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
